welcome to man-made Horrors Beyond
Comprehension hi I'm a molecular
biologist and today we're going to talk
about brain organoids made in a lab and
whether or not they experience
consciousness
brain organoids are brain structures
made from stem cells so we take some
stem cells on a plate and give it the
right materials to make it turn into a
brain however these brains develop eyes
spontaneously that actually receive
information we've also found that these
brain organoids
experience pain and stimuli unlike your
own brain they do however have brain
waves and we can watch them thinking of
course it's fairly rudimentary if you
get enough brain matter in one place
it's going to start interacting with
itself we've also been able to make
things like tear ducts that are
Standalone organoids that are actually
able to function which may be valuable
in transplants in the future our
findings that the brain organoids which
are really more like an organism at this
point their spontaneous production of
more advanced neural tissue like eyes
could be helpful for targeted tissue
development for things like repairing a
spinal cord
however there is the consideration that
when you make a brain organoid let's say
for treatment of a traumatic brain
injury you are essentially making a
smaller less developed version of your
brain made of the same cells
hypothetically we could take those very
same stem cells and make another U if we
really wanted to it's not that hard I
know how
all of this information has web
scientists to consider whether or not
brain organoid should have moral status
and be treated with respect when we're
experimenting on them or whether we
should experiment on them at all what do
you think